## A Bold, Centered Title

avec un sous-titre à la française

#### 1. Profile.

Chin We Niammeng
Gendefale
Degr Bachelor
Worlsing a Experiment (10 years total)
Mobil a 68 16 28 69 4
Emaileddieu@yahoo.com.cn

#### 2. Skills Summary.

I have more than five years working experienced in J2EE application development. Besides the outstanding knowledge of J2EE platform and Oracle database, I also master a lot of low level detail about Operating System Kernel.

# 2.1. J2EE Experience. I have more than five years' experience of developing enterprise application in J

For Application Server, I usually use Tomcat in development environment and use clustered Oracle 10g Application Server in system testing environment. I am also familiar with WebSphere Application Server; I become an IBM certified Solution Developer – WebSphere Studio, V5.0 since October of 2004.

## 2.2. Oracle Database. I believed in solid foundation and I think solid knowledge of database is importa

since that, I become the authority of Oracle database, I have resolved many application performance issue, most of them are caused by BAD SQL statement. I conducted the training to share my knownledge on Oracle. Help them to understand how a SQL statement is executed and how to measure the performance of a SQL statement.

2.3. Design Skills. I have good understanding of classic GOF Design Patterns and J2EE patterns. It helps a lot in understanding the architecture of my projects and other frameworks used in projects. But I treat design pattern as a way to help you resvole the problem beautifully

I got better understanding of Object Oriented Analysis and Design after I mastered design patterns. Source code reading improve my understanding of design pattern, e.g. Visitor pattern and Interpretor pattern are widly used in javac implementation. 3

- 2.4. English Skill I can apply English in daily work fluently as a second language. I not only can read and write technical document fluently in English, but also can communicate with native speaker in conference call.
- 2.5 Certificates. I do not believe the Certificate is a good measure of my skill, but I do think persuing a certificate can help you learn the knowledge systematically and quickly.

DateCertificateSNowne Serial Number

2008 POMP (Project Management Professional)

2006@facle DB92,98,87,91

2004 BM Certified Solution Developer

—WebSphere Studio, V5.0

 2004\$69P (Sun Certified Java Programmer)
 409182

 2003@Htified A3van@d Programmer
 02-81-13-021

 2002@Htified Programmer
 0121400294

#### 3. Work Experience

I started my first full-time IT job from March 15, 2004, till now I have more than five years experience on J2EE platform. Before that, I have worked in Phamaceutical industry for almost 5 years.

#### 3.1. Shanghai Bleum Inc. (October 6, 2004–Now)

I have worked in BLEUM for more than 4 year. I joined Bleum as a junior developer, and gradually grow up to senior developer, technical leader, Architecture, Project manager.

## 3.1.1. Project Manager (May 8, 2008-Now)

I start to manage the pro

## 3.1.2. Architect (October 8, 2007–May 8, 2008)

I am the technical leader of this project. My major responsibility is designing, performance tuning, and Integration testing of related modules.

## 3.1.3. Technical Leader(May 8, 2006-May 8, 2007)

This project is to add new feature — PDF printing for a WEB site, and to change the looking and feel by using more pop up window. The PDF printing is a big challenge for us until we found a tool called PD4ML, which supports convesion from dynamic JSP content to PDF. We also verified that it can works well in the load of about twenty concurrent users.

I am the technical leader of this project. My major achievement is the PDF printing solution based on PD4ML, which can successful convert the JSP page to PDF document.

#### 3.1.4. Senior Software Engineer (October 8, 2005–May 8, 2006)

This project is to optimize performance of an existing application, since customer is not satisfied with the performance of the existing system. We got following lessons and experience about application performance tuning. First, we should consider performance requirement and perform load test in construction phase; Second, the load test should be based on highly-simulated environment, including same amount of data in database. Third, Hibernate may generate some unnecessary table joins, the solution is to use native SQL instead of HQL in such case. Last but not the least, all the SQL Statement, including the SQL statement generated by Hibernate, should be reviewed to decide whether existing index is enough or not and what new index we need to add.

I am the technical leader of this project. I not only improved the performance of the application (several SQL query speeds up more than ten times after tuning), but also gain a lot of hand on experience on Oracle database.

## 3.1.5. Software Engineer (December 6, 2004–October 8, 2005)

The architecture this project is a little special, the business layer is located in Tibco Bizwork server, and Application server basically is a client of the web service published by Tibco Bizwork. The major challenge in this project is to resolve the issues in using Axis, for example, memory leak issue. We also developed a mock mechanism to develop and test WEB layer when the business layer is not ready. (Business layer is joint-developed simultaneously by another two teams, one is in America and the other is in Singapore.)

I am the major developer of this project. I researched on Axis and give training about Axis to team members in the design phase.

#### 3.2. Shanghai Zhongxin Development Inc. (March 15, 2004–October 6, 2004)

The application is deployed on Oracle 9i Application Server in the local area net. It is used to manage all kind of registry and approve of Shanghai Production Security Administration Bureau. The Project achieved success in the use of Struts Framework, which saves us a lot of work. I am in charge of implementing the Business Flow module and System Manage module.

My responsibility includes Designing, Coding, Unit/Integration testing of related module.

## 3.3. Shanghai Zhongxi Pharmeceutical Inc. (May 28, 2001–March 12, 2004)

In this period, I worked in Marketing Department providing academic support for new drugs. In my non-working time, I continually learning Java programming language and other Computer Science subject, and got the certificate of Programmer and Advanced Programmer. Then I started to be involved in the following IT projects in my leisure time.

## 3.3.1. Chinese Chess Game On Internet (2003/09–2003/11).

In this project, we need to develop an Chinese Chess Game application of Server/Client architecture. Its main features include negotiating the regulation, playing between a pairs of player through internet, watching other player's game, counting of time, and requesting to regret the step taken. The player's information is stored in the databases, and every game can been scored automatically by application.

I am in charge of the design and implementation of the client side, implementation of chess rule in the Server side. It took me a lot of time to develop the GUI in client side and to integrate it with the server side.

## 3.3.2. Go Game (Weiqi) Applet (2002/05 - 2002/08).

As an ancient Chinese game, Go is very complex. This program can help the GO players to improve their skills especially skills in "making live" in the board. With the correct strategy stored in the data file, the applet, which is downloaded from internet, can fight against the player, and beat him unless the player has master the skills. This applet improved the interactivity in the teaching and learning of Go related skill.

I am in charge of design and implementation of the program by myself. I also build a simple temporary WEB site to test the Applet.

#### 3.4. Suzhou NO.2 Pharmeceutical Factory (July 14, 2001–May 25, 2001)

During this period, I worked in R&D department and took part in the developing of a new chemical drug – Paroxtine. My major responsibility includes chemical synthesis and chemical analysis. At the same time, I start to self-study Java programming language and other Computer Science subject.

#### 4. Certificates

September 2008 PMP July 2006 OCP

#### 5. Education and Training

July 2008 PMP Training provided by BeiJing Mordern Project Management Interchange Center

1994-1999 Shengyang Pharmaceutical University

Pharmacy English (5 years)

July 2008 PMP Training provided by BeiJing Mordern Project

Management Interchange Center

1994-1999 Shengyang Pharmaceutical University

Pharmacy English (5 years)